Finding Aid for John Garrett Winter papers, 1901-1954
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John Garrett Winter papers 1901-1954
Winter, John Garrett, 1881-1956.
3 linear feet
86348 Aa 2
Professor of Latin and director of the Division of Fine Arts at University of Michigan. Correspondence and newspaper clippings relating to his work and the affairs of University of Michigan; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. John G. Winter (donor no. 977 ) and came to the library in 1958.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
John G. Winter was born in Holland, Mich., on Feb. 14, 1881, a son of Garrett and Janetje de Weerd. He was graduated from Hope College in Holland with an AB degree in 1901. He received an M.A. degree from the University of Michigan in 1904 and a Ph.D. in 1906. He served as an instructor of Greek and Latin at Hope College from 1901 to 1903. In 1906, after receiving his doctorate, Winter became an instructor in Greek and Latin at the University of Michigan. In 1911 he became assistant professor and was promoted to associate professor in 1915 and a full professor in 1919. In addition to his teaching responsibilities, Winter also served as director of the Institute of Fine Arts and of the Museum of Art and Archaeology (now the Kelsey Museum). He served as chairman of the Department of Latin Language and Literature at the University from 1928 until 1950.
In 1929, Winter was named lecturer on the Thomas Spencer Jerome Foundation at the American Academy in Rome. In 1935-36 he was chosen Henry Russel Lecturer at the University of Michigan. He was a member of the Managing Committee of the American School of Classical Studies in Athens, Greece, and a member of the Advisory Council of the American Academy in Rome. In 1944 he was elected president of the American Philological Association.
His publications, in addition to many articles in scholarly periodicals, include: "Myth of Hercules at Rome" (1910), "Life and Letters in the Papyri" (1933), and "Michigan Papyri" (Volume LII. 1936). He was editor of T.S. Jerome's "Aspects of the Study of Roman History" (1923) and general editor of "Michigan Studies" (Humanistic Series).
He died March 23, 1956.
The Winter collection is comprised to six series: Correspondence, Institute of Fine Arts; Museum of Archaeology; Organizational Activities; Biographical / Miscellaneous; and Lectures, speeches, writings.
Subjects:
American Philological Association.; Ars Islamica.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Classical Studies.; University of Michigan. Division of Fine Arts.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. University Museum.; University of Michigan. Scientific Club.; Winter, John Garrett, 1881-1956.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Seabury, Samuel, 1873-1958.; University of Michigan--Commencements--1933.; Winter, John Garrett, 1881-1956.
Contributors:
Adams, James P. (James Pickwell), 1895-1969.; Adams, Randolph Greenfield, 1892-1951.; Aga-Oglu, Mehmet, 1896-1949; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Bennett, Wells Ira, 1888-; Bishop, William Warner, 1871-1955.; Boak, Arthur Edward Romilly, 1888-1962.; Bonner, Campbell, b. 1876.; Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.; Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.; D'Ooge, Martin Luther, 1839-1915.; Effinger, John Robert, 1869-1933.; Ettinghausen, Richard.; Gomberg, Moses, 1866-1947.; Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.; Karpinski, Louis Charles, 1878-1956.; Kelsey, Francis W. (Francis Willey), b. 1858.; Keniston, Hayward, b. 1883.; Kraemer, Casper John, 1895-1958.; Kraus, Edward Henry, 1875-1973; Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), b. 1888.; Lloyd, Alfred H. (Alfred Henry), 1864-1927.; March, Benjamin Franklin, 1899-1934.; Pattengill, Albert Henderson, 1842-1906.; Reeves, Jesse Siddall, 1872-1942; Rice, Warner Grenelle, 1899-; Robbins, Frank Egleston, 1884-; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Sanders, Henry A. (Henry Arthur), 1868-1956.; Warner, Langdon, 1881-1955.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - Undated fragments (Box 1)
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1907-1933 with family members (Box 1)
  - 1901-1940, 42 folders (Box 1)
  - 1941-1954, 11 folders (Box 2)
- Institute of Fine Arts
  - Budget 1932/1933-1945/1946 (Box 2)
  - Clippings 1931 Student Sculpture (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
    - 1929-1937 (Box 2)
    - 1938-1942 (Box 2)
    - 1943-1946 (Box 2)
  - Development Fund (Carnegie Corporation Grant) 1929 (Box 2)
  - Exhibits
    - Ninth Annual Exhibition of Sculpture 1938 (Box 2)
    - Wells M. Sawyer Exhibit 1936 (Box 2)
    - Exhibits, undated 1938, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Exhibit 1940-1941 Chinese art (Box 2)
  - Fairbanks, Professor Award 1933, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Inventory of Art Collections by Miss Hubbard 1933, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Library 1929 (Box 2)
  - Material for Report to President 1934-1935, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Reorganization 1931 (Box 2)
  - Reports to the President 1929-1946 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers undated, 1935 (Box 2)
- Museum of Archaeology
  - Annual reports 1932-1949 (Box 2)
  - Budget 1929/1930-1938/1939 (Box 2)
  - Duties of Secretary, Committee on Research undated (Box 2)
- Organizational Activities
  - Advisory Council to the Committee on the School of Classical Studies of the American Academy in Rome 1930-1932 (Box 2)
  - American College Society of Print Collectors
    - Correspondence 1930-1942 (Box 2)
    - Chairman's reports undated, 1937 (Box 2)
  - American Philological Association
    - Minutes 1933-1949 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence 1940-1949 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 2)
  - American School of Classical Studies in Rome 1943, 1946 (Box 2)
  - C.L. Freer Research and Publication Fund 1932-1945 (Box 2)
  - Committee on Scholarly publications 1935-1948 (minutes) (Box 2)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts 1933, 1940 (Box 2)
  - International Association of Papyrologists 1949 (Box 2)
  - Scientific Club 1935-1949 (Box 2)
- Biographical / Miscellaneous
  - Biographical material (Box 3)
  - Photographs: Portraits and photograph of Winter presenting doctor of laws degree to Samuel Seabury, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Obituary tributes, for friends and colleagues 1927-1954 (Box 3)
  - Faculty resumes of colleagues undated, 1936-1943 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous committee reports undated, 1934-1948 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous committee minutes 1927, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Information Sheet (Faculty Time Report) 1931 (Box 3)
  - Travel diary from trip to eastern seaboard 1931 (Box 3)
- Lectures, speeches, writings
  - Lecture notes
    - Latin literature undated, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Latin literature II undated, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - "Schools and Schoolmen Before the Renaissance," 1916 (Box 3)
    - Twentieth Century Club of Detroit (Box 3)
    - "Cromlechs and the Grave-Circle at Mycenae," undated (Box 3)
    - "Saturnalia," undated (Box 3)
    - "On the Track of Ulysses," undated (Box 3)
    - Archaeology 1927 (Box 3)
    - Classical literature (Box 3)
    - Excavation notes of Barracks of Vigiles (Box 3)
    - History of Painting (Box 3)
    - Rome (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 3)
  - Commencement address undated (Box 3)
  - Works by Winter
    - "Augustine's Confessions," undated (Box 3)
    - "A Point in Boswell's Favor," undated (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous articles and poetry undated, 1913, 1934 (Box 3)
    - "The Prodromus of Nicolaus Steno's Dissertation," 1916 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous writings by others (Box 3)
  - Miscellanea (Box 3)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Adams, James P. (James Pickwell), 1895-1969.
Mar. 29, 1945, Apr. 24, 1945, June 19, 1945, July 18, 1945, July 26, 1945, Aug. 1, 1945, Sept. 12, 1945, Oct. 3, 1945, Oct. 19, 1945, Oct. 24, 1945
Feb. 15, 1946, Mar. 13, 1946, Mar. 18, 1946, Apr. 8, 1946, May 11, 1946, Apr. 1, 1947, Sept. 19, 1947, June 20, 1949, Nov. 14, 1949, Jan. 19, 1950
Adams, Randolph Greenfield, 1892-1951.
Feb. 15, 1946, May 15, 1944, Apr. 29, 1944, Sept. 18, 1943, June 24, 1943, May 7, 1942, Feb. 25, 1942, Apr. 20, 1940, Apr. 17, 1940
Aga-Oglu, Mehmet, 1896-
Apr. 24, 1934, Mar. 24, 1936, Dec. 3, 1937, Apr. 21, 1938, Feb. 18, 1938, Jan. 29, 1937, Oct. 2, 1935, Aug. 12, 1936, Apr. 29, 1936, Apr. 9, 1936, Nov. 19, 1935, Apr. 23, 1936, Jan. 18, 1936, Nov. 19, 1925, Aug. 24, 1935
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
Jan. 24, 1907, Feb. 25, 1907, June 21, 1907, June 22, 1908
Bennett, Wells Ira, 1888-
Oct. 13, 1938
Bishop, William Warner, 1871-1955.
Jan. 17, 1924, Nov. 7, 1928, Nov. 14, 1928, Nov. 21, 1928, Nov. 30, 1928, Nov. 27, 1928, Apr. 8, 1929, May 16, 1929, Oct. 10, 1930, Feb. 21, 1931, Mar. 27, 1931, May 15, 1931, Oct. 24, 1931, Oct. 28, 1947
Boak, Arthur Edward Romilly, 1888-1962.
Oct. 26, 1924, Mar. 8, 1925, Feb. 26, 1931, July 19, 1932, July 21, 1932, Dec. 10, 1941, Aug. 19, 1942, Oct. 11, 1951
Bonner, Campbell, b. 1876.
June 15, 1907, June 22, 1907, Sept. 6, 1907, Sept. 12, 1908, July 20, 1913, July 30, 1913, July 13, 1917, Apr. 30, 1919, Aug. 11, 1919, Feb. 27, 1922, Mar. 13, 1922, May 7, 1922, May 20, 1922, July 1, 1922
Aug. 6, 1926, Jan. 9, 1927, Feb. 10, 1927, Feb. 11, 1927, Feb. 15, 1927, Apr. 15, 1927, Oct. 23, 1927, Jan. 19, 1928, Jan. 22, 1928, Jan. 24, 1928, Feb. 13, 1928, Feb. 15, 1927, Feb. 16, 1928, May 16, 1928, May 28, 1928, June 29, 1928
Sept. 13, 1929, Oct. 15, 1929, Feb. 27, 1930, Mar. 27, 1930, June 17, 1930, Aug. 1, 1930.Aug. 8, 1930, Oct. 6, 1931, Jan. 15, 1932, Jan. 23, 1933, Aug. 3, 1933, May 29, 1934, Mar. 7, 1938, Mar. 8, 1944, Feb. 6, 1947, Feb. 7, 1947, Sept. 18, 1948
Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.
Oct. 29, 1920, Apr. 25, 1921, May 20, 1921.June 1, 1921, June 6, 1921, June 27, 1921, Dec. 26, 1922, June 21, 1923, June 9, 1924, June 17, 1924, July 1, 1924, July 28, 1924, Sept. 17, 1924
Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.
May 22, 1942
D'Ooge, Martin Luther, 1839-1915.
Mar. 14, 1905, Dec. 23, 1910, Jan. 4, 1911, Feb. 10, 1911, Apr. 15, 1911, May 26, 1911, Aug. 7, 1912, Jan. 1, 1913, Apr. 12, 1913, Aug. 26, 1913, Jan. 5, 1914, June 30, 1914, Feb. 2, 1915, Apr. 5, 1915
Effinger, John R. (John Robert), 1869-1933.
Dec. 11, 1918, Dec. 20, 1918, Oct. 23, 1920, Apr. 4, 1922
Ettinghausen, Richard.
June 26, 1946, Nov. 5, 1946, Jan. 30, 1946, Jan. 5, 1946, Mar. 27, 1946, Apr. 9, 1946, Dec. 12, 1945, Oct. 31, 1945, Sept. 18, 1945, Aug. 8, 1945, Aug. 2, 1945, June 21, 1945, June 27, 1945, May 2, 1945, July 3, 1944, Mar. 14, 1945
Nov. 27, 1944, Oct. 7, 1944, Sept. 6, 1944, July 29, 1938, Mar. 14, 1944, Apr. 19, 1943, Jan. 6, 1943, June 15, 1942, July 29, 1942, Feb. 9, 1942, Oct. 20, 1941, Oct. 3, 1941, May 19, 1941, May 17, 1941
July 31, 1939, Aug. 8, 1939, May 8, 1939, July 17, 1938, June 16, 1939, July 6, 1942, July 29, 1942
Gomberg, Moses, 1866-1947.
Mar. 26, 1936, May 20, 1937
Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.
May 16, 1907.May 21, 1907, Oct. 25 1907, Jan. 6, 1909, Oct. 4, 1910, Oct. 19, 1935, Nov. 25, 1935, Nov. 26, 1935, Nov. 29, 1935, Dec. 9, 1935, Nov. 23, 1936, Nov. 24, 1935, Jan. 31, 1938, Feb. 20, 1940, Jan. 4, 1945
Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.
July 7, 1921
Karpinski, Louis Charles, 1878-1956.
Apr. 20, 1948
Kelsey, Francis W. (Francis Willey), b. 1858.
Dec. 30, 1904, Oct. 30, 1905, Oct. 14, 1907, July 16, 1907, Nov. 5, 1907, July 3, 1909, Oct. 15, 1910, Apr. 19, 1910, Oct. 4, 1910, Dec. 26, 1912, July 17, 1914, Apr. 4, 1915, July 26, 1915, Sept. 4, 1915, Mar. 17, 1916, Oct. 28, 1916
Jan. 28, 1922, Jan. 31, 1922, Feb. 2, 1922, Feb. 25, 1922, Mar. 20, 1922, Apr. 7, 1922, Apr. 11, 1922, Apr. 15, 1922, May 13, 1922, Sept. 16, 1925, Dec. 9, 1925
Mar. 5, 1926, Mar, 13, 1926, Apr. 29, 1926, Aug. 10, 1926, Sept. 10, 1926, Sept. 14, 1926, Nov. 16, 1926, Nov. 20, 1926, Jan. 5, 1927
Keniston, Hayward, b. 1883.
July 15, 1942, Aug. 26, 1942, Nov. 16, 1945, Feb. 27, 1946, Mar. 22, 1946, Apr. 1, 1946, Apr, 30, 1946, Aug. 7, 1946
Kraemer, Casper John, 1895-1958.
Jan. 24, 1928, March 13, 1928
Kraus, Edward Henry, 1875-
Oct. 31, 1936, May 10, 1937, Jan. 28, 1943, Feb. 1, 1934, Nov. 9, 1934, Mar. 18, 1935, Aug. 24, 1942, Feb. 9, 1944, Oct. 24, 1944, Nov. 9, 1944, Dec. 19, 1933
Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), b. 1888.
June 22, 1927, June 25, 1927, Nov. 16, 1928, Feb. 2, 1927, June 9, 1928, June 13, 1928
Lloyd, Alfred H. (Alfred Henry), 1864-1927.
Mar. 15, 1905, Feb. 19, 1911, Jan. 21, 1916, Mar. 8, 1917, May 20, 1925, June 17, 1925
March, Benjamin Franklin, 1899-1934.
June 2, 1933, Oct. 24, 1934, Oct. 5, 1934, Apr. 26, 1934, Aug. 5, 1933, Aug. 8, 1933, Aug. 18, 1933, Aug. 14, 1933
Pattengill, Albert Henderson, 1842-1906.
Dec. 20, 1904, Apr. 14, 1905, May 30, 1905
Reeves, Jesse Siddall, 1872-
June 5, 1937, Dec., 7, 1937, Dec. 3, 1940, Jan. 6, 1941, Jan. 29, 1942
Rice, Warner Grenelle, 1899-
Nov. 4, 1946, July 20, 1944, Dec. 29, 1942, Aug. 18, 1942, Oct. 13, 1941, Feb. 2, 1950
Robbins, Frank Egleston, 1884-
June 8, 1912, Oct. 25, 1921, Feb. 27, 1922, May 26, 1922, Nov. 29, 1922, June 1, 1923, Apr. 1, 1927, July 20, 1929, Aug. 1, 1929
Oct, 22, 1930, Oct. 24, 1930, Oct. 29, 1930, Mar. 25, 1931, Nov. 16, 1931, Dec, 26, 1931, Nov. 26, 1932, Dec. 8,1932, Dec. 15, 1932, Aug. 5, 1933, Oct. 27, 1933, Nov. 3, 1933, Mar, 12, 1934, May 22, 1934, May 7, 1934, Sept. 30, 1934, Oct. 17, 1934, Oct. 19, 1934, Oct. 23, 1934, Oct. 28, 1934
Mar. 7, 1935, Mar. 11, 1935, Mar. 27, 1935 Mar. 28, 1935, Apr. 2, 1935, May 1, 1935, Aug. 2, 1935, Oct. 9, 1935, Oct. 17, 1935, Oct. 18, 1935, Nov. 15, 1935, Nov. 19, 1935, Nov. 21, 1935, Mar. 4, 1936, May 20, 1936, June 24, 1936, June 28, 1936, July 2, 1936, Oct. 19, 1936, Nov. 5, 1936
Feb. 1, 1937, Feb. 4, 1937, Feb. 8, 1938, Mar. 25, 1939, Nov. 11, 1939, Nov. 16, 1939, Nov. 22, 1939, Nov. 24, 1939
Mar. 13, 1940, Nov. 23, 1940, Mar. 4, 1941, Oct. 6, 1941
Jan. 20 1942, May 2, 1942, May 8, 1942, May 19, 1942, May 20, 1942, May 21, 1942, June 16, 1942, June 26, 1942, Aug. 6 1942 Aug. 24, 1943, Sept. 1, 1942, Dec, 3, 1942, Dec. 4, 1942
Oct. 7, 1943, Dec. 14, 1944, Feb. 26, 1946, Nov. 6, 1946, Mar. 21, 1947, Mar. 25, 1947, Nov. 5, 1947, Nov. 13, 1947, Nov. 20, 1947, Dec. 3, 1947, Feb. 2, 1948, Mar. 11, 1948, May 3, 1948, June 7, 1949, June 14, 1949, Oct. 12, 1949
Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.
Jan. 18, 1917, Apr. 23, 1930, Feb. 11, 1931, Jan. 15, 1932, Jan. 26, 1932, July 11, 1932, Sept. 27, 1932, Nov. 11, 1932, Nov. 14, 1932, Nov. 15, 1932, Nov. 18, 1932, Mar. 6, 1933, Mar. 8, 1933, July 25, 1933, Sept. 20, 1933, Oct. 4, 1933, Oct. 10, 1933, Oct. 25, 1933
May 11, 1934, May 14, 1934, Dec, 17, 1934, Jan, 27, 1936, Feb. 20, 1936, Apr. 4, 1936, May 25, 1936, June 4, 1936, July 11, 1936, July 24, 1936 Sept. 30, 1936, May 17, 1938, June 11, 1938, Sept. 25, 1939
Jan. 4, 1940, Mar. 18, 1940, Apr. 13, 1940, Nov. 1, 1940, Nov. 13, 1940, Nov. 14, 1940, Nov. 15, 1940, Mar. 27, 1941, Apr. 1, 1941, May 2, 1941, May 21, 1941, June 10, 1941, June 16, 1941, June 27, 1941, Sept. 5, 1941, Sept. 26, 1941, Sept. 29, 1941, Oct. 3, 1941, Oct. 10, 1941, Nov. 10, 1941, Nov. 26, 1941, Nov. 27, 1941
Jan. 28, 1942, Feb. 10, 1942, Feb. 13, 1942, Feb. 16, 1942, Feb. 17, 1942, Mar. 26, 1942, May 21, 1942, May 29, 1942, June 18, 1942, June 22, 1942, June 24, 1942, Oct. 31, 1942, Nov, 6, 1942
Jan, 30, 1943, May 15, 1943, July 21, 1943, Oct 5, 1943 Mar. 23, 1944, Apr. 5, 1944, Apr. 26, 1944, May 9, 1944, July 13, 1944, Sept. 27, 1944
Jan. 29, 1945, Apr. 9, 1945, Apr. 17, 1945, May 22, 1945, June 7, 1945, June 13, 1945, Feb. 26, 1946, July 1, 1946, July 31, 1946, Aug. 14, 1946, Sept. 24, 1946, Sept. 26, 1946
Apr. 28, 1947, May 20, 1947, Aug. 14, 1947, Jan. 22, 1948, Oct. 3, 1949, Nov. 3, 1949, Jan. 17, 1916, Mar. 7, 1932, Aug. 16, 1933, Sept. 1, 1938, Mar. 20, 1944
Sanders, Henry A. (Henry Arthur), 1868-1956.
Oct. 9, 1915, Dec. 31, 1915, Jan. 12, 1921, Oct. 27, 1922.May 3, 1923, Sept. 30, 1928, Oct. 13, 1928, Oct. 27, 1928, Nov. 12, 1928, Nov. 15, 1928, Dec. 15, 1928, Dec. 22, 1928, Feb, 6, 1929, Feb, 9, 1929, Mar. 8, 1929, Mar. 20, 1929, Apr. 1, 1929, Apr. 5, 1929, Apr. 8, 1929, May 20, 1929, June 26, 1922, July 19, 1929
July 10, 1930, Oct. 8, 1930, Oct. 24, 1930, Nov. 11, 1930, Nov. 21, 1930, Jan. 7, 1931, Feb. 18, 1931, Mar. 13, 1931, Mar. 25, 1931, June 14, 1931, Feb. 17, 1932, June 10, 1936
Warner, Langdon, 1881-1955.
Nov. 4, 1937